Register of the Aleksandr Polovet͡s papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1980-2016, undated
  - Literary figures, 1981-2016, undated
    - Polovets, Alexander, undated (Box-folder 14: 59)
      1 color print.
    - Popov, Evgenii, 2000, undated (Box-folder 14: 60)
      5 color prints depicting Popov with Alexander Polovets, Vasily Aksyonov, and others.
    - Popovsky, Mark, 1988, undated (Box-folder 14: 61)
      5 color prints depicting Popovsky alone and with Alexander Polovets and other people.
    - Prigov, Dmitri, undated (Box-folder 14: 62)
      3 color prints depicting Prigov alone, with Alexander Polovets, with Alexander Zholkovsky.
    - Puschkarsky, Nikolai, undated (Box-folder 14: 63)
      2 color prints depicting Puschkarsky giving a lecture and being interviewed by Pyotr Veghin for Panorama.
    - Ratser, Boris, undated (Box-folder 14: 64)
      2 color prints, one of which depicts Ratser with Alexander Polovets.
    - Rein, Evgenii, undated (Box-folder 14: 65)
      1 color print depicting Rein reciting his poetry at Peredelkino at an evening in honor of Bulat Okudzhava.
    - Rishina, Irina, undated (Box-folder 14: 66)
      1 color print depicting Rishina at Peredelkino.
    - Roziner, Felix, undated (Box-folder 14: 67)
      5 color prints depicting Roziner with Alexander Polovets and others.
    - Rubina, Dina, undated (Box-folder 14: 68)
      1 color print depicting Rubina with Alexander Polovets and others.
    - Rybakov, Anatoly, 1991 (Box-folder 14: 69)
      1 color print depicting Rybakov at his dacha in Peredelkino.
    - Savitski, Dmitri, undated (Box-folder 14: 70)
      1 color print depicting Savitski at the editorial office of Panorama.
    - Schuman, Tomas, 1985-1990, undated (Box-folder 14: 71)
      6 prints (1 BW and 5 color) depicting Schuman alone, with Alexander Polovets, with other people.
    - Sedykh, Andrei, undated (Box-folder 14: 72)
      2 color prints depicting Sedykh alone and with Alexander Polovets and Valerii Vainberg.
    - Semenov, Iulian, undated (Box-folder 14: 73)
      2 prints (1 BW an 1 color) depicting Semenov with Alexander Polovets and with an employee of Panorama.
    - Sevela, Efraim, 1998, undated (Box-folder 14: 74)
      7 color prints depicting Sevela alone, with Alexander Polovets, and with other people.
    - Shargorodsky, Lev, undated (Box-folder 14: 75)
      7 color prints depicting Shargorodsky with Alexander Polovets and other people.
    - Shchekochikhin, Iurii, undated (Box-folder 15: 1)
      3 color prints depicting Shchekochikhin alone, with Alexander Polovets, and with Yevgeny Yevtushenko and Alexander Polovets.
    - Sidorov, Evgenii, undated (Box-folder 15: 2)
      1 color print depicting Sidorov with Alexander Polovets and Anatoly Gladilin.
    - Simonov, Aleksei, undated (Box-folder 15: 3)
      1 color print depicting Simonov pointing to a map of Russia.
    - Sinyavsky, Andrei, undated (Box-folder 15: 4)
      2 color prints depicting Sinyavsky with his wife Mariia Rozanova, Alexander Zholkovsky, and Olga Matich.
    - Sokolov, Sasha, undated (Box-folder 15: 5)
      3 color prints depicting Sokolov with Alexander Polovets, with Viktor Sokolov and Alexander Polovets, and with Vasily Aksyonov and Alexander Polovets.
    - Sorokin, Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 15: 6)
      1 color print depicting Sorokin during a reading at the “Podval” Club in Moscow.
    - Suslov, Ilya, undated (Box-folder 15: 7)
      6 prints (1 BW and 5 color) depicting Suslov with Alexander Polovets, Mark Rozovsky, Iurii Oislander, and other people.
    - Tkachenko, Alexander, undated (Box-folder 15: 8)
      3 color prints depicting Tkachenko with Alexander Polovets, Arkady Vaisberg, John Gladd, and other people.
    - Tolstaya, Tatyana, 1994, undated (Box-folder 15: 9)
      2 color prints depicting Tolstaya with Alexander Polovets, Vasily Aksyonov, and Alexander Genis.
    - Trifonovich, Dushko, undated (1980s) (Box-folder 15: 10)
      1 color print depicting Trifonovich with Alexander Polovets.
    - Vail, Peter and Alexander Genis, 1994, undated (Box-folder 15: 11)
      11 color prints depicting them together, with Alexander Polovets, and with other people.
    - Vainberg, Valerii, undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
      2 color prints depicting Vainberg with an unidentified employee of Novoe Russkoe Slovo and with Alexander Polovets.
    - Vasiliev, Boris, undated (Box-folder 15: 13)
      1 color print depicting Vasiliev with Alexander Polovets.
    - Vcherashnii, Rostislav, 1994 (Box-folder 15: 14)
      1 BW print depicting Vcherashnyi in his office in Moscow.
    - Veghin, Pyotr, 2001, undated (Box-folder 15: 15)
      4 color prints depicting Veghin alone, with Valerii Begishev, and with a guest of Panorama.
    - Vishnevskii, Vladimir, 1987-2004, undated (Box-folder 15: 16)
      9 color prints depicting Vishnevskii with Alexander Polovets, Arkady Arkanov, Boris Sichkin and other people.
    - Voinovich, Vladimir, undated (Box-folder 15: 17)
      1 BW print depicting Voinovich with Alexander Polovets and Naum Korzhavin.
    - Voznesensky, Andrei and Zoya Bogoslovskaya, 2004, undated (Box-folder 15: 18)
      3 color prints depicting Voznesensky with Alexander Polovets and Zoya Bogoslovskaya, as well as Zoya Bogoslovskaya and Irina Muravieva with Alexander Polovets.
    - Yevtushenko, Yevgeny, 1997, undated (Box-folder 15: 19)
      9 color prints depicting Yevtushenko with Alexander Polovets and other people.
    - Zholkovsky, Alexander, undated (Box-folder 15: 20)
      2 color prints depicting Zholkovsky with Alexander Polovets and by a swimming pool with Olga Matich and other people.
  - Political figures and events, 1980-2016, undated
    - Inventory prepared by Alexander Polovets, 2016 (Box-folder 15: 21)
    - American officials, 1999-2000, undated (Box-folder 15: 22)
      14 prints (4 BW and 10 color) depicting Alexander Polovets with congressmen, senators, supervisors, district attorneys, police chiefs and other officials. See inventory in folder XX for exact identification.
    - Arbatov, Georgy, undated (November 1992) (Box-folder 15: 23)
      2 color prints depicting Arbatov, Director of the Institute of the USA and Canada of the Russian Academy of Sciences, being interviewed in his Los Angeles hotel room by Alexander Polovets and Ilya Baskin.
    - Baker, James Addison ("Jim"), 2002, undated (Box-folder 15: 24)
      3 color prints depicting Baker with Alexander Polovets and at the USA-Russia Commercial Energy Summit in Houston, Texas.
    - Berezhkov, Valentin, 1987, undated (Box-folder 15: 25)
      2 color prints depicting Berezhkov, Stalin’s interpreter, with Alexander Polovets at the offices of Panorama and autographing a copy of his memoirs.
    - Bonner, Robert C., undated (1986) (Box-folder 15: 26)
      2 color prints of Bonner, United States Attorney for the Central District of California being interviewed by Alexander Polovets.
    - Bradley, Thomas J. ("Tom"), undated (Box-folder 15: 27)
      1 color print depicting Los Angeles Mayor Bradley during a telephone conversation with Soviet Jewish refuseniks in Moscow.
    - Clinton, William Jefferson ("Bill"), 1995, undated (Box-folder 15: 28)
      12 prints (1 BW and 11 color) depicting President Clinton at the White House speaking with Alexander Polovets, White House visitors, as well as single photographs of Alexander Polovets.
    - Events in support of the re-election of Ronald Reagan, undated (1984) (Box-folder 15: 29)
      10 color prints depicting Pat Buchanan, Jeanne Kirkpatrick, Dennis Prager, Alexander Polovets and other Jewish emigrants from the USSR at the Century Plaza in Los Angeles.
    - Hershensohn, Stanley Bruce ("Bruce"), 1991, undated (Box-folder 15: 30)
      8 color prints depicting Hershensohn during his run for the U.S. Senate. Includes photographs of him with Alexander Polovets and Panorama staff.
    - Independent Jewish press, undated (Box-folder 15: 31)
      3 color prints of a demonstration in support of an independent Jewish press in Los Angeles.
    - Jewish functionaries and events, undated (Box-folder 15: 32)
      9 prints (1 BW and 8 color) depicting HIAS officials, Orthodox rabbi Meir Kahane speaking with Alexander Polovets, Simon Wiesenthal with Alexander Polovets, and others.
    - Kalina, Alexander I., undated (Box-folder 15: 33)
      1 color print depicting the engineer and developer of the Kalina cycle thermodynamic process at a power plant in San Francisco.
    - Kulikov, Viktor Georgievich, undated (1996) (Box-folder 15: 34)
      2 color prints depicting Marshall Kulikov during his visit to Los Angeles meeting with soviet veterans and with Alexander Polovets at the offices of Panorama.
    - Lukin, Vladimir, 2000, undated (late 1990s) (Box-folder 15: 35)
      3 color prints depicting Lukin, then a member of the State Duma of the Russian Federation, being interviewed by Alexander Polovets and meeting with Panorama staff.
    - National Newspaper Association Conference, Washington, DC, 1995 (Box-folder 15: 36)
      4 color prints depicting presenters and attendees.
    - Mamadaev, Yaragi, undated (1991) (Box-folder 15: 37)
      1 color print depicting a representative of the government-in-exile of the Chechen Republic of Ichkeria.
    - News media, undated (Box-folder 15: 38)
      3 color prints depicting Alexander Polovets giving an interview to a Los Angeles TV station, the owner of a New York Russian-language radio station reading articles from Panorama to his listeners, and journalist Larry Stammer preparing an article about Panorama.
    - Press conference, 1984 (Box-folder 15: 39)
      2 color prints depicting a joint press conference given by FBI Director William Webster and US Attorney Robert C. Bonner regarding Soviet spies Nikolai and Svetlana Ogorodnikov.
    - Refuseniks (Jewish and other), 1980, undated (Box-folder 15: 40)
      12 prints (1 BW and 11 color) depicting refuseniks such as Iosif Begun, Erik Edel’, Oleg Emeliamov and A. P. Fedoseev.
    - Russian officials and public figures, 1989-1999, undated (Box-folder 15: 41)
      11 prints (1 BW and 10 color) depicting Prime Minister Stepashin, cosmonaut German Titov, Consul-General Iurii Popov and others. Alexander Polovets appears in some of the photographs. See inventory in folder XX for exact identification.
    - Safarov, undated (Box-folder 15: 42)
      2 color prints of an unidentified deputy chairman of an unidentified committee of the State Duma of the Russian Federation conversing with Alexander Polovets and holding a copy of Panorama.
    - Simon Wiesenthal Center, Los Angeles, 2000 (Box-folder 15: 43)
      4 color prints depicting the opening of the monument to Holocaust victims.
    - Wilson, Peter Barton ("Pete"), undated (1982) (Box-folder 15: 44)
      2 color prints depicting Wilson during his campaign for the U.S. Senate. Includes a meeting with members of the Los Angeles Jewish community and with Alexander Polovets and Sy Furman.
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1981-2016
  Recordings (transferred to CDs) of Alexander Polovet͡s’ conversations with writers, and cultural and political figures. In two parts, arranged alphabetically in each part by last name.
  - Part 1
    - Inventory of recordings in Part 1, providing biographical information on each interviwee, date of conversation, recording length, and brief content summaries of the conversations (Box-folder 9: 12)
      Provides biographical information on each interviewee, date of conversation, recording length, and brief content summaries of the conversations.
    - Al'burt, Lev, 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his chess career, the political situation in Russia, his publishing ventures and plans for the future. 1 file. Duration: 49 minutes.
    - Aleksin, Anatolii, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation about literary matters, the role and fate of the older generation of Soviet writers, the reforms of Khrushchev and Gorbachev. 2 files. Duration: 2 hours.
    - Arbatov, Georgy, 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation about Soviet leaders with whom he worked, Perestroika, the work of his institute, Russian-American relations, his feelings about dissidents, and his forecast of future Russian policies. 2 files. Duration: 2 hours.
    - Arkanov, Arkady, 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation about different aspects of his biography, emigration, cultural relations, and contacts with his fellow-countrymen living abroad. 2 files. Duration: 138 minutes (58 min. + 50 min.).
    - Avtorkhanov, Abdurakhman, 1987 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his book “The Last Empire” devoted to the national and colonial policy of Soviet imperialism. 1 file. Duration: 38 minutes.
    - Barshai, Rudolf, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his musical life, difficulties encountered during the Soviet period due to censorship and bureaucratic hurdles. 2 files. Duration: 31 minutes (21 min. + 10 min.).
    - Belov, Yuri, 1997 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his decision to leave the USSR, the difficulties he encountered, life in the USA, and comparison of the Russian and American theatrical systems. 2 files. Duration: 51 minutes (31 min. + 20 min.).
    - Berezhkov, Valentin, 1997 (Box 16)
      Conversation about key moments and figures in Soviet history, conditions in pre-World War II Europe. 2 files. Duration: 2 hours, 45 minutes (1 hr. 2 min. + 33 min.).
    - Emelyanov, Oleg, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the details of his decision to leave the USSR by any means possible, his experiences in Turkey and America, and plans for the future. 2 files. Duration: 55 minutes.
    - Erofeyev, Victor, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the history of Panorama, current conditions in Russia, offers to collaborate with American publishers. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 21 minutes (1 hr. + 21 min.).
    - Gladilin, Anatoly, 1994 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the murder of Sergei Mazhorov, a prominent Russian businessman. 1 file. Duration: 19 minutes.
    - Gorodnitsky, Alexander, 1996 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the fate of songs performed by their authors in Russia and their role as a guardian of the Russian language and culture in Germany, Israel, and the USA. 1 file. Duration: 37 minutes.
    - Guberman, Igor, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation about literary prizes, his trial and exile, emigration to and life in Israel, and contemporary Russia. 3 files. Duration: 1 hour, 27 ninutes (43 min. + 3 min. + 41 min.).
    - Kandel, Feliks, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation about current conditions in Russia and literary matters. 2 files. Duration: 59 minutes (43 min. + 16 min.).
    - Kasparov, Gary, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation about different aspects of the political situation in Russia. 3 files. Duration: 2 hours, 4 minutes (51 min. + 45 min. + 28 min.).
    - Khalif, Lev, 1983 (Box 16)
      A conversation comparing the role and place of authors in the Soviet Union and the USA. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 25 minutes.
    - Konchalovsky, Andrei, 1980s-2000s (Box 16)
      Wide-ranging conversations about his personal and professional life in Russia and the USA, including his movies and American cinema. 4 files. Duration: 3 hours, 8 minutes (47 min. + 47 min. + 47 min. + 47 min.).
    - Koreneva, Elena, 1990 (Box 16)
      A conversation about different aspects of her acting career, her acting studio, and impressions of various Russian cultural figures. 3 files. Duration: 2 hours (45 min. + 45 min. + 45 min.).
    - Lundstrem, Oleg, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his passion for jazz, his jazz orchestra in Shanghai and in the USSR, and impressions of their tours abroad. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 50 minutes (52 min. + 48 min.).
    - Mamadaev, Yaragi, 1991 (Box 16)
      Conversation about what led to war in the Chechen Republic and the mistakes of the Yeltsin government. 3 files. Duration: 1 hour (7 min. + 44 min. + 9 min.).
    - Nadein, Vladimir, (1990s) (Box 16)
      3 files. Duration: 55 minutes of Nadein in conversation with Sergei Rakhlin.
    - Nadein, Vladimir, (1990s) (Box 16)
      Conversation with this famous journalist on a wide range of issues, including the economics of the post-Soviet newspaper business. 2 files. Duration: 50 minutes of Nadein in conversation with Alexander Polovets.
    - Padua, Genrikh, 1991 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his work as a defense attorney and legal issues arising from the disparity between a new social order and outdated laws. 2 files. Duration: 51 minutes.
    - Rachikhin, Vladimir, 1985 (Box 16)
      Conversation about various aspects of his biography, such as being accused of murder, convicted, and sent to prison. 3 files. Duration: 2 hours, 20 minutes (1 hr. and 10 min. + 40 min. + 30 min.).
    - Rodnina, Irina, 1993 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the “hierarchy” of different sports in the USSR, the difficulty of being a sports star, and relations between sportsmen and their trainers. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 36 minutes (48 min. + 48 min.).
    - Rozengurt, Michael, 1991 (Box 16)
      Conversations dealing with various aspects of water and hydrology. 8 files. Duration: 3 hours, 30 minutes.
    - Shemiakin (Chemiakin), Mikhail, 2005 (Box 16)
      Conversation dealing with the artist’s move from France to the USA, the return to traditional values, and the relationship between the new and the old in the artist’s work. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Sichkin, Boris, undated (1990s) (Box 16)
      2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 42 minutes (57 min. + 42 min.).
    - Smirnoff, Yakov, 1989 (Box 16)
      Discussion of stand-up comedy and the difficulties of working with an audience with a different linguistic and cultural backround, and state of mind. 4 files. Duration: 55 minutes.
    - Vidov, Oleg, 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his movie career, creative freedom, immigration to the USA, and feelings about post-Soviet Russia. 4 files. Duration: 1 hour, 20 minutes (40 min. + 40 min.).
  - Part 2
    - Inventory of recordings in Part 2 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Aksyonov, Vasily, 1981-1990 (Box 16)
      - Presentation at "Russian Literature in Exile" conference, 1981 (Box 16)
        1 file. Duration: 28 minutes.
      - Interview by A. Polovets and Alena Aksyonova, 1987
        2 files. Duration: 42 minutes (30 min. + 12 min.).
      - Conversation with A. Polovets, 1990
        1 file. Duration: 1 hour.
      - Answers to questions posed by Panorama editorial staff, 1989
        2 files. Duration: 63 minutes (31 min. + 32 min.).
    - Baskin, Ilya, 1986 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the difficulties of making it in Hollywood, the differences between movie making in the Soviet Union and the USA, and his plans for the future. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour.
    - Bitov, Andrei, 1991 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the August coup attempt against Gorbachev, general issues of USSR-USA relations, American assistance, and the Moscow PEN-Center. 1 file. Duration: 21 minutes.
    - Chernov, Mikhail, 1986 (Box 16)
      Conversation about his escape from the USSR and obtainment of asylum. 2 files. Duration: 40 minutes.
    - Chudakova, Marietta, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the role of literature under current conditions, the historical fiction of Valentin Pikul, working with graduate students, and increasing the role of books in the lives of Soviet people. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 20 minutes (43 min. + 37 min.).
    - Evtushenko (Yevtushenko), Yevgeny, 1998 (Box 16)
      Conversation recalling their first meeting, the post-Stalin “Thaw”, some of the successes of Soviet literature despite oppression, and other literary matters. 1 file. Duration: 1 hour and 5 minutes.
    - Fain, Samuil, Dr., 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation on the importance of increasing coverage of sexual topics in the Russian-language press, both quantitatively and qualitatively. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Foster, Ludmila, 1981 (Box 16)
      Conversation about Voice of America broadcasts to the Soviet Union, measures to combat Soviet jamming, and the importance of feedback from Soviet listeners. 1 file. Duration: 17 minutes.
    - Furman, Igor, 1997 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the work of the Russian American Medical Association. 1 file. Duration: 45 minutes.
    - Gladilin, Anatoly, 2011 (Box 16)
      Telephone conversation about the “shestidesiatniki” (1960s generation)and their unique role in Soviet literature, emigration past and present, and Gladilin’s feelings about Los Angeles and Panorama. 1 file. Duration: 47 minutes.
    - Jackson, Henry, Senator, 1981 (Box 16)
      Conversation on current political affairs, with an emphasis on the condition of Jews in the USSR and the problems of their emigration. 1 file. Duration: 23 minutes.
    - Kasparov, Gary, 1989 (Box 16)
      Conversation on the professionalization of sports in Russia. 1 file. Duration: 20 minutes.
    - Kashpirovsky, Anatoly, 1989 and 1990 (Box 16)
      Conversation on a wide range of topics, including contemporary politics and his career as a psychotherapist, hypnotist and psychic healer. 4 files. Duration: 1 hour, 43 minutes (35 min. + 30 min. + 30 min. + 8 min.).
    - Korzhavin, Naum, 1987 (Box 16)
      Conversation on literary matters, visits to the USA by Soviet writers, and the low level of social engagement among emigrants from the USSR. 2 files. Duration: 40 minutes (35 min. + 5 min.).
    - Kruglyi stol chitatelei v gazete “Panorama” (Round table with Panorama readers), 1994 (Box 16)
      Discussion of issues related to the publication, content, and distribution of the newspaper. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 30 minutes (45 min. + 45 min.).
    - Kulikov, Viktor, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation on the key moments in the military career of this Marshal of the Soviet Union and his thoughts on military strategy and politics in general. 1 file. Duration: 1 hour, 5 minutes.
    - Limonov, Edward, ca. 1995 (Box 16)
      Conversation regarding this author’s novel “Eto ia, Edichka!” (It’s Me, Eddie), contemporary Russian literature, his reading habits, and other issues. 2 files. Duration: 65 minutes (32 min. + 33 min.).
    - Literary Conference in Los Angeles, 1981 (Box 16)
      Presentations by writers Rafail Nudelman, Viktor Nekrasov, and Nikolai Bokov. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes (10 min. + 10 min. +10 min.).
    - Livshits, Aleksandr, 1999 (Box 16)
      Conversation on the failure of Russian liberals, Russo-American relations, and current Russian political problems. 2 files. Duration: 1 hour, 30 minutes (45 min. + 45 min.).
    - Lukin, Vladimir, 1993 (Box 16)
      Conversation on various aspects of Russian-American relations, military doctrine and use of nuclear weapons, the Chechen conflict and territorial integrity of Russia. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Lundstrem, Oleg, 1988 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the fate of professional musicians in the USSR, his family, and ancestors. 1 file. Duration: 11 minutes.
    - Lvov, Arkadii, 1987 (Box 16)
      Conversation regarding his literary career, his interest in the history of Odessa Jewry, and the diffences between the editing process in the USSR and the USA. 1 file. Duration: 25 minutes.
    - Menshov, Vladimir, ca. 1992 (Box 16)
      Conversation with the director and his wife Vera Alentova about the current state of the Russian cinema, the transition to a market economy, and their impressions of their trip to the USA. 1 file. Duration: 41 minutes.
    - Mikhoels, Natalia, 1985 (Box 16)
      Conversation on the 95th anniversary of the birth of her father, theater director Solomon Mikhoels, centered on his biography and the need to preserve is heritage. 1 file. Duration: 33 minutes.
    - Minkin, Aleksandr, 1996 (Box 16)
      Conversation about the state of journalism in contemporary Russia, professional ethics, and the role of new entrepreneurs. 1 file. Duration: 30 minutes.
    - Petrova, Liubov, 1995 (Box 16)